Would
you recommend starting TRT after using
peeds for more than seven years in my
20ies? No, I am off since about 6 years,
but I feel low libido. I tried for a
short time, 3 months, 100 mgram test.
Okay. So one thing that's common in the
what I've seen from the bodybuilding
space and this is just what I've
observed is that there's this mentality
which is that if you blast with a really
high dose of steroids then you cruise at
like a really low level of TRT and then
that's going to level out as healthy.
That's not how it works. Um that's like
saying if I drink 50 beers on Saturday
and no beers for the other six days then
I'll be fine. Um, no it doesn't work
like that. So the like unless you're
really sensitive to it, 100 milligrams a
week of testosterone ananth is probably
hypogonadal territory. I mean that's
that's too low for most people. So
unless you're really sensitive to it,
there would be no therapeutic response
to being on 100 milligrams of
testosterone and out there a week. um
that's like a a overcompensating cruise
level that bodybuilders do, but that
would make that would basically be
hypogonatal for most people. Now, I
can't tell you that you should or
shouldn't go on TRT, but you absolutely
should look into it. In in my
experience, if men do steroid cycles
prior to the age of 25, especially if
they're doing it long term and like
perma blasting for a long period, the
chance of you coming off that and and
and having recovery of optimal and
levels, even if you do whatever people
would consider like the best PCT in the
world, I mean, I I wouldn't I wouldn't
bet on those odds. Um I I'd bet a
significant amount of money against it.
Um, and I don't gamble. So that that
would be a you definitely want to look
into it. And the first mistake you made
was just doing your own TRT and thinking
that was going to work. So don't do
that. Um, learn from your previous
mistake of, you know, hijacking your
endocrine system and damaging your
hormone production and go to someone who
is a specialist and a good provider or a
good clinic. And, you know, this group
is full of them. you know, between my
clinics in in Australia and Europe, uh
the great partnered clinics that we all
speak about in the UK, clinics like Eden
Clinic or AlphaGenics or Balance My
Hormones. Um and then all the great
providers we have in the US in this
group, any of these providers who are,
you know, worth what they do. They're
not going to judge you or or not give
you access to treatment because of your
history. They're going to go, "Oh, this
guy probably does need treatment." I
mean, I started TRT when I was 25. Um,
and if you've used anabolic steroids in
your youth and you've damaged your
endocrine system and you're still in
your 20s, it's really important for you
to seek treatment if if you do need it
and you are indeed hypogonatal because
otherwise you're going to age and
deteriorate at such a rapid rate that by
the time you get into your 30s and 40s,
you're going to be in a pretty poor
state of health. So, a good clinic and
provider will be very compassionate to
this. They will work with you. Um, if
you worked with one of my clinics, we'd
give you the hard word from the get-go
and say once you start prescribed TRT,
you can't go back and just blast
steroids because you're giving your word
to your provider of what you're going to
do. So, if you want to do TRT, be a good
patient. Do it responsibly. Listen to
your provider. But this is absolutely
something that you should look into.
Hey,
hey, hey.